Hello friends, in today's video we will
discuss about dividend.
In this video, we will discuss the details of the companies which are giving dividend in the next few days.
So let's start
friends.  The first company is HCL
Technology.  SC Technology has
announced a dividend of ₹12 per share.  That means it is
giving ₹12 per share.  And
he has kept its record date as 17 October 2025.  That
means those who have purchased its shares by October 16, 2025 will become
eligible for this dividend.  This
HCL Tech is a large cap company.  NFT
is also a part of 50 and if we look at its market cap, it has a
large market cap of ₹11215 crores.  And if we
talk about its number of shareholders,
friends, then
its number of shareholders is 885835.  If we
talk about shareholder investment, the
average shareholder investment is Rs 46 lakh.
If we talk about the shareholding pattern in this, then the
promoter has 60% stake.
FIIs hold 18.5% and
DIIs hold 16%.  The second
company is Platinum One Business Service.
This company is giving dividend at ₹2 per share.
And the record date it has set is
17 October 2025.  That means those who
buy by October 16, 2025 will be
eligible for this dividend.
Friends, this is an SME company and its
market cap is Rs 27 crore and if we
talk about the total number of shareholders in it, it is
132.  If we
look at the average investment, the share holder is Rs 20 lakh and the
promoter's share is 73%.  The rest
is all public.  Next company we
talk about.  Anand Rathi Wealth.  Anand Rathi
Wealth has announced a dividend of ₹ on its shares
and the
record date for this is October 17, 2025, which means that anyone who
buys its shares by October 16, 2025 will be eligible for it.
Its market cap is ₹25,963 crore.  It
is a mid cap company.  If we talk about its number of
shareholders, then
its number of shareholders is 74,121.  And if the
shareholders look at the investment, it goes up to Rs
35 lakh.
If we look at the shareholding pattern in this,
friends, the promoter has a stake of 42.7%.
FIIs have invested 5.56%
and DIIs have invested 8.73%.  The
rest is all public.
Next let's talk about the company.
Rama FSFS Rama FSFS has announced dividend of 50 paise per share.  The
record date they have set for this is 21 October
2025.  That means those who buy this share by October 20 will become
eligible for it.  And if we
talk about its market cap, it is ₹602 crores.  It
is a very small company.  If we
look at the total number of shareholders in this, friends, it
is 13,915.  So the number of shareholders
is very high in this market cap.  So if we
look at the share holder investment, it is only Rs 4
lakh.  That means the
average shareholder investment is Rs 4 lakh.  The promoter's
stake is 75%.  FII is only 0.07%.
End DII is 0.03%.  The rest is all retail.
Next let's talk about the company.
Tips Mus.  Tips Mus has given dividend of ₹4 per share to friends.
He has given the record date as 21 October 2025.  Those who
buy the same till 20th October will become eligible for this.
It is a small cap company with a market cap of ₹6822 crore.  If you
look at its number of shareholders, it is
69564.  That
means it has a very large number of
shareholders.  If we look at the investment,
how much is the shareholder's investment on the average shareholder?  So it is only worth Rs 10
lakh.  The promoter's stake is 64%.
FII share is 8.16%.  DII's
is 5.03%.  The rest is all public.  Friends, let us
discuss about the next company,
that is Tech Mahindra.  Tech
Mahindra has announced a dividend of ₹15 per share
and the record date is
October 21, 2025.
Its market cap is ₹141412
crore.  It is a large cap company.  If we look at the number of
shareholders, it is 48176.  And if we
look at the average investment, the share
holder's investment is Rs 19 lakh.  If we
look at the shareholding pattern, the promoter holds 35%.
FII is quite good at 23.28%
and DII is even more at 32.13%, the
rest is public.
Friends, let's talk about the next company, that is
Oberoi Realty, which is giving dividend of ₹2 per share.  The
record date is October 21, 2025.  The
market cap is Rs 6274.
That means the
market cap is Rs 6274 crore.  And the number of
shareholders is
9 sorry 97531
number of shareholders.  Let's
talk about the next company, friends, ICIC
LBR is a general insurance company.  The
stock is paying dividend at 6.5.
He has set the record date as 23 October 2025.  The market cap
is quite good.  99522 has a
market cap of Rs 582 crore.  That means it is a
large cap company.  And friends, the number of
shareholders is very high.   There are
240,980
number of shareholders.  If we
look at the average investment per share holder, it is Rs 41
lakh.  The promoter holds 51% stake.
FIIs hold 24%.  BII holds
17.5% stake.  The rest is all public.  Let's
discuss the next company.  KSVS
India.  KSVS India is giving dividend on shares at ₹5,
friends, and
they have kept the record date as 23rd October.  The market
cap of this company is Rs 767 crore.  Microc
is a small company.  But friends, the number of
shareholders is 61853.  That
means the market cap on H
is very high number of shareholders.  If we
look at the average investment per share holder, it is
₹1 lakh.  That means the entire retail is
filled with it.  The promoter holds 59%
stake.  FII's is 0.5.  The DII
is 0.01.  The rest is all public retail.   Let's
discuss the next company.
Uniparts India is
giving share dividend at ₹2.5 friends.
Friends, it is giving a dividend of ₹2.5.  Its market cap is
₹80,487.
Its market cap is ₹2369 crore.
Ok?  It is a small cap company.  But the
number of shareholders is 880487.  Ok
?  If we look at the average investment per share
holder, it is only Rs 3 lakh.   The
promoter's stake is 65.66%.
FII's is 1.83% and DII's
is 5.95%.  The rest is retail and public.  So
friends, these are all the companies which are going to
give dividend in the next seven days.  One should never
invest by looking at the dividends.  Is
fundamental growth good for investment?  Decisions have to be taken after considering how the company will grow in the future.
Dividend is the only
decision maker
for investment.  So friends, that's all for today's video.
If you like our content then
please subscribe to the channel.
Like, share, comment on the video.
See you in the next video.  Thank
you guys.